70. Charlie Chaplin – A Serious Man When you think of Charlie Chaplin, you probably
think of his expressive face or his funny penguin-like waddle. Charlie Chaplin was very
good at making people laugh, but he had a serious side too. Chaplin was passionately
anti-Nazi and urged the rest of the world to take the Nazi threat seriously. Later,
he made anti-war statements in some movies. While he was beloved for his silly antics,
his serious political views sometimes got him into trouble. The Great Dictator was the
only film of its time to make fun of Adolf Hitler and the Nazis. Chaplin mocks Hitler,
but uses a speech at the climax of the movie to push America into the war. While telling
his soldiers, Hitler's soldiers in mill metaphor, not to be used by a dictator, he
at the same time repeatedly asks the world to fight for democracy, peace and freedom.
The speech was a brave statement, but America was not at war with Germany then. Many people
wanted to stay out of the fight. Chaplin began to be watched by some authorities.
If Chaplin was too pro-war in 1940, authorities found him to be too anti-war later during
the Cold War between the Soviet Union and the United States. Movies like Monsieur Verdu
made anti-war statements, causing authorities in the United States to harass Chaplin. Authorities
followed and searched Chaplin many times without ever finding hard evidence. Chaplin went from
being America's darling to being harassed and threatened for his political views, but
he didn't stop doing what he thought was right. Chaplin, despite all the trouble, ended up
as well-loved as ever. Those who opposed him, however, are either forgotten or ashamed.